Guide to the China Records Project Miscellaneous Personal Papers Collection
Yale University Divinity School Library
China Records Project Miscellaneous Personal Papers Collection
1834-2012
RG 8
Yale University Divinity School Library
169
(387 boxes)
The China Records Project Miscellaneous Personal Papers Collection is an open collection. It currently contains material from more than 325 individuals, primarily Protestant missionaries to China. The time period covered is approximately from 1834 to 1998. The China Records Project was initiated by the National Council of Churches of Christ in the U.S.A in 1968. The aim of the project was to insure the preservation of the personal records of former missionaries to China and to provide a central repository where these papers would be available to historians. The Yale Divinity School Library was chosen as this central repository in 1969 and has continued to solicit and accept China-related papers since that time.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gifts of various donors.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Biographical / Historical
The China Records Project was initiated by the National Council of Churches of Christ in the U.S.A in 1968. The aim of the project was to insure the preservation of the personal records of former missionaries to China and to provide a central repository where these papers would be available to historians. The Yale Divinity School Library was chosen as this central repository in 1969 and has continued to solicit and accept China-related papers since that time.
The first Protestant missionary to China was Robert Morrison, who arrived in 1807. Elijah Coleman Bridgman was the first American missionary to China, sent by the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions in 1829. Protestant missionaries were active in China until ca. 1950 when they were forced to leave by the new Communist government.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of more than 380 boxes, with no individual accounting for more than three linear feet. Some collections that were formerly part of this record group have now been given separate record group numbers.
The papers in the first series of this collection are arranged alphabetically by name. When the information was available, each missionary's sending agency, geographical location in China and period of service have been noted. A key to abbreviations used to represent the mission sending agencies is given below. The designation "L" in the indications of period of service means that these are approximate dates derived from listings in available copies of the Directory of Protestant Missions in China (1902, 1904-05, 1908-11, 1916, 1921, 1923-24, 1926-30, 1932-36, 1940, 1950). An asterisk following the name of an individual means that at least a portion of the papers of that individual are available on microfilm (and therefore accessible via Interlibrary Loan)and through the Adam Matthew "China Through Western Eyes" database: http://www.researchsource.amdigital.co.uk/ASChina.
Some photographs in the collection have been digitized and are available through the Internet Mission Photography Archive (IMPA) - http://www.usc.edu/isd/archives/arc/digarchives/mission/. If availability in IMPA is indicated, search the IMPA database using the name of the individual, e.g., search for "Edward Abbott Papers."
The records in this collection include biographical information, correspondence, diaries and journals, writings, printed material, tape recordings, artifacts, photographs and maps. The medical, educational and evangelical work of both men and women missionaries in China is reflected in the material. Social issues such as footbinding, opium reform, education of women, cruelty to animals and child labor are also touched upon. The material is particularly valuable for the descriptions of daily missionary life and work which it provides. Missionary opinion about major social and political issues is less prevalent in the material, although personal accounts of some political events (such as the Boxer Rebellion and the internment of missionaries by the Japanese) are given.
The Oral History Transcripts of Series II are from the China Missionaries Oral History Project conducted at Claremont Graduate School in Claremont, CA in the early 1970s.
For a full list of personal papers that are part of the China Records Project see: https://web.library.yale.edu/divinity/china-papers.
Abbreviations for missions agencies used in this finding aid:
ABCFM -American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions
ABFMS -American Baptist Foreign Missionary Society
ACM -American Church Mission (Episcopal)
ALM -American Lutheran Mission
AUG -Augustana Synod Mission
BMS -Baptist Missionary Society (British)
CBM -Church of the Brethren Mission
CCC -Church of Christ in China
CIM -China Inland Mission
CLS -Christian Literature Society
CMML -Christian Missions in Many Lands
CMS -Church Missionary Society
ChCC -China Continuation Committee of the National Missionary Conference
EPM -English Presbyterian Mission
FCMS -Foreign Christian Missionary Society
FFMA -Friends' Foreign Mission Association
LCMS -Lutheran Church Missouri Synod; pre 1947 MELCM; pre 1927 ELSM
LMS -London Missionary Society
LUM -Lutheran United Mission
MEFB -Methodist Episcopal Church
MES -Methodist Episcopal Church South
MGC -Mennonite General Conference
MMS -Methodist Missionary Society
PN -American Presbyterian Mission, North
PS -American Presbyterian Mission, South
RC -Roman Catholic
RCA -Reformed Church in America
RCUS -Reformed Church in the United States
SBC -Southern Baptist Convention
SDA -Seventh Day Adventist Mission
SVMM -Student Volunteer Movement
UCC -United Church of Canada
UCMS -United Christian Missionary Society (Disciples of Christ)
WFMS -Women's Foreign Missionary Society of Methodist Episcopal Church
YM -Yale in China Association
YMCA -Young Men's Christian Association
YWCA -Young Women's Christian Association
Arrangement
I. Papers of Individuals: A-G
II. Papers of Individuals: H-M
III. Papers of Individuals: N-Z
IV. Oral History Transcripts
Existence and Location of Copies
Several sets of papers in this collection have been microfilmed and are now also available in digital format at http://www.researchsource.amdigital.co.uk/ASChina. The Adam Matthew digital database is accessible only to the Yale community; microfilm can be requested via interlibrary loan. Individuals whose papers are available on microfilm and digitally are noted with an asterisk.
Child labor -- China; Communism -- China; Footbinding -- China; Missions -- China; Missions; Opium abuse -- China; Women -- Education -- China; China -- History -- Boxer Rebellion, 1899-1901; Educators; Evangelists; Missionaries; Nurses; Physicians; Barbour, Dorothy Dickinson; Barbour, George B. (George Brown), 1890-1977; Craighill, Lloyd R. (Lloyd Rutherford), 1886-1971; Craighill, Marian G, 1890-1981; Gray, G. F. S.; Hartwell, C. (Charles), 1825-1905; Hartwell, Emily Susan, 1859-1951; McClure, Jeanie Graham, 1890-1971
- Papers of Individuals: A - G, Series I
  - Abbott, Edward
    - Collection of 57 photographs taken in China between 1896 and 1900 at various Episcopal missions, medical and educational institutions, churches, incl. St. John's College, Shanghai; Boone School, Wuchang; St. Peter's Hospital, Wuchang; St. Peter's Church, Hankow. Buildings, faculty, students, clergy, etc. represented. Also of interest: Imperial Examination cells at Nanking, Chinese Prayer Book Revision Committee. Following individuals are included in photos: Ingle, Pott, Partridge, Thomson, Graves, Huntington, Roots, Littell, faculty of St. John's College, 1897. (Some photos available in IMPA: http://www.usc.edu/isd/archives/arc/digarchives/mission), 1896-1900 (Box 248, Folder 1-2)
  - Adams, Archibald
    Biographical / Historical
    Biog. info: ABFMS; Suifu and Kiating, Szechwan; (1914-1926)
    - Photographs - scenes primarily in Szechwan, 1920s (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Photographs - people, occupations; Szechwan, 1920s (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Photographs - people, occupations; Szechwan, 1920s (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Photographs - scenes and people; primarily Szechwan, 1920s (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Photographs - Buddhist funeral, 1920s (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Photographs - Buddhist funeral, 1920s (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Photographs - people, occupations; Szechwan, 1920s (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Photographs - buildings, scenes; Kiating, Peking, 1920s (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence to mother, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Typescript reports of his work, 1918-1925 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Typescript articles by AA, incl. "Suifi Under Fire Again", 1917-1919 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Published articles by AA, 1919-1937 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Collected material: "Sketches of Nanking" - Papers of the Literary Department of the Nanking Women's Club, 1922-1923 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Adams, Arthur
    Biog. info: ABFMS; Hanyang, Hopo, Swatow; (1904-1944)
    - Circular letter from Arthur and Mabel Adams, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Adams, Marie
    Biog. info: MEFB; Taianfu, Peking; (1915-1950)
    - Photographs - Views in China, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Photographs - China flowers (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Photographs - The Chart of Old Peking, Apr 1935 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Photographs - Chinese Temples, Aug 1934 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Published book by MA: "The Jumping-off Place", 1979 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Collected material: "Chinese festivals", "Chinese funeral", "Chinese wedding", "Shop signs in China", "Snapshots from China", 1938-1948 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Collected material: "The Chart of Old Peking", "Art Calendar", 1935-1939 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Adolph, William
    Biog. info: 1922-1926 Professor of Chemistry at Shantung Christian University, Tsinan, China; 1927-1928 Professor of Chemistry at the University of Nebraska; 1929-1942 Professor of Chemistry at Yenching University, Peking, China; 1947(?)-1950 Professor, Peiping Union Medical College, Peiping, China
    - Correspondence (circular), 1922-1951 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Typescripts: "Adolph family diary excerpts", 1935-1947 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Collected material: "A guide to scientific living", 1963 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Pamphlets: "A Guide to Yenching University", programs, incl. snapshots of William Adolph, 1920-1939 (Box 302, Folder 1)
  - Aeschliman, Edward and Myrle
    Biog. info: Methodist missionaries 1919-1950, stationed in Peking and Tientsin. EA was Methodist pastor and district director, worked with students.
    - Correspondence with extended family, 1919-1950 (Box 343, Folder 1-14)
    - Correspondence to daughter Patricia, 1945 -1950 (Box 343, Folder 15-20)
    - Correspondence to daughters Barbara, Dorothy, and Myrle (wife), 1947-1949 (Box 343, Folder 21)
    - Circular letters, 1920-1950 (Box 343, Folder 22-23)
    - Biographical information (Box 343, Folder 24)
    - Photographs of China and Africa, 1920's, 1953, 1954 (Box 343, Folder 25)
    - Newsclippings and collected items, 1921-1951 (Box 343, Folder 26-27)
  - Albert, Martin*
    Biog. info: Am. Pres. Mission, North
    - Typescript articles by MA, incl."Currency difficulties in the years 1920-1942", "Forty years ago in Hwaiyuan", "Refugees 1937", "Banking between Hwaiyuan and Shanghai 1938-1942", "Two incidents - Kuling", "Get you up to a high mountain, O Zion, Isa. 40: 9", "Kuling mountaoins -'Lions' leap'", "Mountain pools - Dragon pool", "Mountain pools - Incense mills pool", "Kuling camping trip" (written 1979), "Finding a falls - Kuling", "Up Taishan" (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Collected material: "The story of Hope Hospital", 1948 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Allgood, Roy and Petra
    Biog.info: Roy Allgood was headmaster of the Kuling-American School, Kuling, Kiangsi from 1931 to 1939
    - Letters compiled by Rita Allgood Tubbs (daughter): "How Essential to my Happiness - Allgood Family Correspondence Concerning the Kuling Years 1931-1939" - photocopies (Box 365, Folder 1)
  - Alsup, Alice
    Biog. info: MES Soochow, Ku. Huchow, Che. Shanghai (L.1919-L.1940)
    - Photograph (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence to mother, family etc., 1926-1949 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Circular letters from Alice Alsup, 1919-1937 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1924-1966 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Anderson, Mrs. Carl L.
    - Photographs, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Atwood, Irrenius J., M.D.*
    Biog. info: ABCFM Shansi (1882-1913) (d.1913)
    - Correspondence, 1908-1913 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Typescript writings incl. "Tribute to Dr. I.J. Atwood (1913)", "Journal of Miss Susan Rowena Bird (martyred at Taiku, July 31st, 1900)", "The Shansi Mission" (1907), untitled sketch re. China, 1900-1913 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Avery, Benjamin Parke
    - Writings: notes from China by BPA, 1874-1875 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Collected material incl. "The Markham Review" etc., 1969 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1875-1876 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Bailey, Mrs. Paul H.
    Biog. info: ACM Shanghai St. John's Univ. (L.1916-L.1923)
    - Correspondence, printed material, pamphlets, photos, plaque, coins, 1912-1948, 1961 (Box 20)
  - Baker, John Gilbert Hindley*
    Biog. info: CMS Canton, Kunming (1934-1944) St. John's Univ., Shanghai (1947-1949) Lingnan Univ., Canton (1949-1951)
    - Correspondence: Letters from JGHB to his parents in England; from Canton, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence: Letters from JGHB to his parents in England; from Canton; Lingnan University, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence: Letters from JGHB to his parents in England; from Lingnan University, Canton; Hong Kong; Holy Trinity College, Canton, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence: Letters from JGHB to his parents in England; from Holy Trinity College, Canton, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence: Letters from JGHB to his parents in England; from Canton; CMS hospital, Kunming, Yunnan; Calcutta, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence: Letters from JGHB to his parents in England; from Kunming, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence: Letters from JGHB to his parents in England; from Kunming, 1941-1943 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence: Letters from JGHB to his parents in England; from Kunming; Calcutta; New York, 1944-1946 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence: Letters from JGHB to his parents in England; from US; from St. John's University, Shanghai, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence: Letters from JGHB to his parents in England; from St. John's University, Shanghai; Canton, 1948-1949 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Typescript writings: "On the study of church history in China (May 1983) (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Typescript writings: Draft of proposed book "It happened to us in China", re. Baker, his wife and her family, 1900-1951 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Balme, Howard
    Balme was an English Baptist missionary based in Shansi.
    - Letter to J.H. Oldham describing Anti-Christian movement in China and its relation to educational work, 1925 (Box 376, Folder 13)
  - Barbour, George B. and Barbour, Dorothy Dickinson, (Mrs. George B.)
    Biog. info: LMS Peking Yenching Univ. (1920-1934)
    - Introductory Material; biographical sketch of George Brown Barbour by Hugh Barbour, 1968-1970 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Corres., writings, pr. mat. arranged chron. and topically, 1911 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Corres., writings, pr. mat. arranged chron. and topically, 1920-1930 (Box 13, Folder 3-12)
    - Corres., writings, pr. mat. arranged chron. and topically, 1931-1938 (Box 14, Folder 1-5)
    - Corres., writings, pr. material related to geology (Box 14, Folder 6-7)
    - Religious Education (Box 14, Folder 8-11)
    - Students (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Customs (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - In China When... (book by George Barbour), 1975 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Typescript drafts for book (2 notebooks), 1911-1925 (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
    - Offprints of articles by George Barbour published in scientific journals, 1929-1949 (Box 15, Folder 3-4)
      Scope and Contents
      Articles include "The Loess Problem of China", "The Taiku Deposits and the Problem of Pleistocene Climates", "Geomorphology of the Nanking Area"
    - Correspondence: Letters and postcards from GB, 1926 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Letters from GB, 1921-1930 (Box 16, Folder 2-5)
    - Correspondence: Letters from G and DB, 1932-1934 (Box 16, Folder 6-7)
    - Samples of accepted correspondence, 1926 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Pamphlets, 1922-1933 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Afterword about China, 1931-1936 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: Letters from G and DB, 1923 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Corres., writings, letters, 1920-1931 (Box 17, Folder 2-4)
    - Correspondence: Letters re. servants, etc., 1921-1927 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Letters from GB, 1923 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Letters from G and DB, 1924-1925, 1931 (Box 17, Folder 7-9)
    - Mss of Mission Study books by Dorothy Barbour for Episcopal Church in USA, 1942 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Letters from G and DB, 1930 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Material for "Toward Day by Day" Epis. daily devotions (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Corres., letters and postcards, 1911 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Letters from GB "Early Days", 1920-1922 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Corres. re. London Mission appointment Yenching University, 1920 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Corres. re. Shanghai student slayings to British legation, Liu Te-yuan, 1925 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Religious Education, 1956-1969 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Collected materials: Non-Chinese pictures (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Notes on talks given by DB on China mostly in Cincinnati, 1942 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Collected Materials: reprint article "The Skull of 'the Peking Man'", 1930 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Photographs and negatives: "Loess and erosion features above Kelgen" (Selected photographs available in IMPA: http://www.usc.edu/isd/archives/arc/digarchives/mission) (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Photographs and negatives: China-Yangtze gorge, etc.- groups-villagers, 1911-1934 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Photographs and negatives: Geology related, China, 1921-1934 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Photographs and negatives: Geology related, China "Kalgen area", 1921-1934 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Photographs and negatives: Geology related, China "Yen tung Shan", "geology films Pen Shan E of Hopei", "Loess negatives used for Nevius Article on Dust", etc, 1921-1934 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Photographs and negatives: Geology related, China "Chait'ang Basin", etc., 1921-1934 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Photographs and negatives: Misc. incl. postcards, some with correspondence, stamps, 1931 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Photocopy of diary kept by Robert and Sarah Dickinson during voyage along South China coast from Hong Kong to Shanghai, 1919 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Barbour, Margaret Hart Bailey
    Biog. info: ACM missionary in Shanghai, St. John's University (ca.1916-1923)
    - Photographs 0001-0017 (Selected photographs available in IMPA: http://www.usc.edu/isd/archives/arc/digarchives/mission) (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Photographs 0018-0089 (Box 20, Folder 2-3)
    - Photographs: Misc. (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Letters to Mrs. Barbour, 1913-1949 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence (collected) Nanking, Chinkiang, etc., 1923-1926 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Shanghai Newsletter, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Collected Materials: "Some aspects of China's Foreign Relations in Long Retrospect", "Round Robin", 1913-1939 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Misc. incl. Congratulations wedding plaque to Ms. Lee from St. Mary's School, string of 20 cash, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Photographs: St. Mary's School Shanghai, 1923 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Bard, B. Theodore and Ruth
    The Bards were Assemblies of God missionaries stationed in north China 1924-1949.
    - Memoir by B.T. Bard: "A Missionary Story About the Bards", 2002 (Box 376, Folder 9)
    - Memoir by Ruth Bard: "In the Service of the King of Kings", 1963 (Box 376, Folder 10)
  - Barnes, Margaret E.
    ABCFM, North China Christian Rural Service Union, T'ungchow
    - 4 circular letters, 1949-1950 (Box 376, Folder 14)
  - Barnett, Eugene E.
    Biog. info: YMCA Shanghai (1910-1936)
    - Typescript report: "The Far East in the Summer of 1940" (Box 20A, Folder 1)
    - Memoirs of EEB Vol. II part 3 (Box 20A, Folder 2)
    - Notes on a visit of EEB to Hankow, 1926 (Box 20A, Folder 3)
  - Bartlett, Myrth
    - Typescript poem by MB: "My Rosary of Amber Beads" (Box 20A, Folder 4)
  - Bartlett, Robert M.*
    Biog. info: ABCFM Yenching Univ. (1924-1927)
    - Photographs: Photos of five Chinese Revolutionists (Box 243, Folder 1)
    - Typescript ms. by RMB: "Chinese Revolutionaries" (Box 243, Folder 2-5)
    - Typescript ms. by RMB: "Jimmy Yen - Humanitarian of the Century" (Box 273, Folder 1-6)
  - Bausum, Euva Evelyn Majors (Mrs. Robert Lord)
    Biog. info: SBC Kweilin (1924-1944); Taiwan (1951-1955)
    - Biographical Questionnaire filled out by her husband (Robert Lord Bausum) for the Southern Baptist Convention Foreign Mission Board, 1972 (Box 20A, Folder 5)
  - Bausum, Robert Lord
    Biog. info: SBC Kweilin (1920-1944); Taiwan (1951-1955)
    - Biographical Questionnaire filled out for the Southern Baptist Convention Foreign Mission Board, 1972 (Box 20A, Folder 6)
  - Bayless, Gertrude
    Biog. info: PN Changsha (1923-1950); taught at high school
    - "Diary-Narrative of my Years on the Foreign Mission Field" (70 pp.) (Box 352, Folder 1)
  - Beach, Frederick P.
    Biog. info: ABCFM Foochow Fukien Christ. U. (1910-1937)
    - Correspondence: Letters from FPB, 1911 (Box 20A, Folder 7)
  - Bear, James E. and Margaret W.
    Biog. info: PS Chinkiang, Shanghai, Tsingtao (1923-1929)
    - Photocopies of correspondence, 1923-1929 (Box 20A, Folder 11)
  - Beck, Karl H.
    Biog. info: RCUS; RCA Yuanling, Yungsui area (1914-1952)
    - Typescript writings: "Memoirs of Hsiang-Si Mission" by Karl H. Beck (1972) Re. Evangelical and Reformed Church's China Mission in Western Hunan (Box 20A, Folder 8)
  - Beech, Joseph and family
    Joseph Beech was an American Methodist missionary serving in China from 1899 to 1941. In 1914, he became one of the founders of the West China Union University, and he served as chancellor of this institution until 1941.
    - Listing of documents held by Beech family as of 5/2011; biographical sketch of Joseph Beecher; photocopies of two circular letters written by Beech, 2011, no date (Box 372, Folder 1)
    - Transcription of "The Personal Diary of Katharine Louise ("Pat") Beech" recounting the Beech family's voyage from China to the U.S., 1927 (Box 372, Folder 2)
    - Excerpts from the personal photo album of Nellie Miriam Decker (Mrs. Joseph Beech) - photocopies of photographs with transcribed captions; DVD of Joseph Beech's video of West China Union University and othe China locations, 1900-1904, ca. 1939-1940 (Box 372, Folder 3)
  - Belcher, Harold and Marian
    Biog. info: ABCFM, Foochow; Belcher (1891-1971) was field treasurer and business agent for the ABCFM mission in Foochow from 1914-1920; he was unable to return to China due to health reasons and from 1921 to 1958 served as assistant treasurer and treasurer of the ABCFM
    - Correspondence: Letters from Harold and Marian Belcher primarily to family members in the US from the Foochow mission, 1914-1919 (Box 22, Folder 1-19)
    - Typescript writings incl. "Christmas in China" (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Collected Material: Manual of the Foochow Dialect, English-Chinese Dictionary of the Foochow Dialect, Union Chinese Hymnal, 1909-1915 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Bell, L. Nelson
    Biog. info: PS Tsingkiangpu, Kiangsu (1916-L.1940)